N. Mohamed Irshad

Phone: +919629219229

E-mail: irshadmohamed93@gmail.com

Nationality: Indian

OBJECTIVE

To be a part of a dynamic organization that facilitates application of my technical and management skills gained through my experiences in India, UAE&Saudi Arabia and enables me to broaden my current capabilities, offering career progression.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Hands-on experience in Operation and Maintenance of

- > 18.9MVA,33/11KV Electrical sub-station
- ➤ 6.6KV,33KV SF6 Circuit Breakers
- HT control panels ,HVAC systems
- ➤ 400KV Switchyard Equipments,11KV VCb breakers,
- ▶ 6.6KV HT motors upto 3.5MW and 11KV outdoor kiosks
- LT Electrical Control Panels
- Irrigation system control panels
- Hands in experience various industries like power plant, steel plant and agricultural sector

WORKING EXPERIENCE:

April 2015 to july 2017

Company: National agricultural development company, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Depertnment:Electrical maintenance Designation: Electrical engineer

- > Operations and maintenance of 33/11Kv indoor electrical sub station
- > Operation and maintenance of LT control panels for center pivot irrigation system
- Guide the group of technicians for various electrical epquniments installations like Three phase ACgenerators LT control panels cable laying and routing
- > Daily inspection of electrical equipment's like Ac generators,3 phase induction motors, circuit breakers, relays and timers for proper operations
- > Control panel maintenance for belt conveyor systems
- Preventive maintenance activities for diesel engine like Mitsubishi and caterpillar used for borewell
- > Supervising the functions of troubleshooting & predictive / preventive maintenance for identifying areas of obstructions and reducing machinery downtime to minimum
- > Troubleshot/repaired/installed High, medium, and low voltage equipment
- Report to manager regarding work completed referring unusual technical or personnel issues

December 2011 - December 2014: junior Engineer/ Electrical Maintenance

Company: Jindal SAW Gulf LLC, Abu Dhabi, UAE Division: Ductile iron pipe manufacturing unit

- > Operation and maintenance of LT single main distribution system
- Maintenance of MCC panels for centrifugal casting machine and annealing furnace
- > Operation and maintenance of 3TON/Hr. capacity gas fired Thermal reclamation system
- PLC based LT control panel wirings of DN 200 to DN 2200 DI pipe finishing line machines like Zinc coating, hydro pressure testing machine, and cement lining machines
- > Assist manager in scheduling work and determining needs for equipment and supplies
- Supervising the functions of troubleshooting & predictive / preventive maintenance for identifying areas of obstructions and reducing machinery downtime to minimum
- Troubleshot/repaired/installed High, medium, and low voltage equipment. Performed calibrations/verifications on temperature, pressure, and flow controls

- As a team worked with Chinese engineers in commissioning and installation of the machinery equipment's supporting them in all engineering aspects
- Report to manager regarding work completed referring unusual technical or personnel issues

July 2009 – July 2011: Electrical Supervisor Company: Jindal saw limited Gujarat india Division: Electrical Operation and Maintenance

- Operation and maintenance of 18.9MVA 33/11kv electrical substation equipment's like 6.3 MVA power transformers 11kv isolating switches 11kv air break switch 11kv vacuum circuit breakers oil circuit breakers SF6 circuit breakers and 11kv outgoing feeders
- Operation and maintenance of 210*2MW Thermal power station equipment's like 6.6kv HT motors upto 3.5MW
- 400kv switch yard systems like lightning arrestor, 400kv SF6 breakers, motor operated isolating switches, Earth switches, disconnecting switches, current transformers and capacitor voltage transformers
- Operation and maintenance of HVAC systems and 11kv outdoor kiosks and fire detection and alarm systems
- > Testing and routing of MV and LV XLPE power cables
- Operation and maintenance of Battery system Battery charger DC loads and DC pumps

EDUCATIONAL & TRAINING

Pursuing 4th year B.E in Electrical Engineering

In Rajasthan Vidyapeeth (Deemed)University ,Udaipur,Rajasthan

Diploma in Electrical Engineering 1st class Honours with 88.88%

Udaya Polytechnic College,

Vellamodi, Kanyakumari, Tamilnadu

(DOTE, 2006-2009 Batch

SSLC (All General Subjects), with of 61%

St.Mary's Higher Secondary School,

Colachel, Kanyakumari, Tamil nadu

(TamilNadu State Board, 2005 - 2006)

Attended Supervisory Skill Development Program at Training Complex, Neyveli Lignite Corporation Limited, Neyveli in the following Topics

- 1 Industrial safety
- 2 Material management
- 3 Finance management

Attended Training program conducted by Japan institute of plant maintenance at Jindal saw gulf llc abudhabi in the following topics

- 1 Total productive maintenance
- 2 General safety awareness
- 3 Industrial waste manegment
- 4 Risk assemment

PROFICIENCY IN COMPUTING TOOLS

Operating System
Windows XP/vista , Ubuntu 10.04,10.10

Office Package MS office 2010Programming Electrical CAD

OTHER SKILL:

- Languages known English, Tami Malayalam and hindi
- Eager and willing to acquire new skills & competencies
- Good communication & listening skills
- > Eminent leadership qualities gained during student & work experiences
- Dedicated team player
- Good motivator

Place: colachel	(MOHAMED IRSHAD)

Date: